<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>The 24 Sock Project</title>
    <link>http://24sockproject.me/</link>
    <description>Recent content on The 24 Sock Project</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 14:46:49 -0230</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://24sockproject.me/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Cotton Socks</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/post/cotton_socks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 14:46:49 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/post/cotton_socks/</guid>
      <description>This pair took me what feels like forever to finish. I think it was mostly because of my attention being elsewhere in my down time, but it seemed like these socks were cursed to take a long time. For a while I didn&amp;rsquo;t know if I&amp;rsquo;d manage to actually wear the cotton socks while the weather was still warm. In any case, they&amp;rsquo;re done now; and that makes eight pairs and sixteen socks completed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinnamon</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/post/cinnamon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jun 2018 11:38:06 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/post/cinnamon/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m really late posting this one, but I finished the pair in May. It&amp;rsquo;s pair seven, socks thirteen and fourteen. I used the FlexiFlips needles again, and I&amp;rsquo;m sold on them now.
This sock came out a little larger than I expected, I think the yarn is a bit thicker than my previous pair.
Finished socks.
   Sock Details      Yarn (main) Regia Pairfect, Cinnamon colourway   Yarn (heel) Patons Kroy Socks, Colour Coal   Pattern Mina&amp;rsquo;s Vanilla Sock Recipe, with high-instep option   Size 64 stitch   Ribbing 2×2 ribbing for 16 rounds (1 3&amp;frasl;4&amp;rdquo;)   Leg Length 64 rounds (6 3&amp;frasl;4&amp;rdquo;) (not including ribbing)   Foot Length 70 rounds (7&amp;rdquo;) (not including toe)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Van Gogh&#39;s Blue Jay</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/post/blue_jay/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2018 07:37:06 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/post/blue_jay/</guid>
      <description>The project is halfway complete. This is pair six, socks eleven and twelve. For these ones I tried out the new addi FlexiFlips DPNs, I&amp;rsquo;m not 100% sure on them yet, so I&amp;rsquo;m going to use them again for the next pair and then possibly write a little about them on there.
Finished socks.
   Sock Details      Yarn (main) Valentina Colour Works Classic Sock, Van Gogh&amp;rsquo;s Blue Jay colourway   Pattern Mina&amp;rsquo;s Vanilla Sock Recipe, with high-instep option   Size 64 stitch   Ribbing 2×2 ribbing for 16 rounds (1 1&amp;frasl;2&amp;rdquo;)   Leg Length 64 rounds (5 1&amp;frasl;2&amp;rdquo;) (not including ribbing)   Foot Length 72 rounds (6 1&amp;frasl;4&amp;rdquo;) (not including toe)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pennants</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/post/pennants/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 08:25:17 -0230</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/post/pennants/</guid>
      <description>Pair number five (socks nine and ten) is done. This one took a little longer, as the pattern took a bit more concentration to not lose my place.
Finished socks.
Pattern close up.
   Sock Details      Yarn (main) H&amp;amp;W Comfort-Wolle Sockenwolle Comfort Color   Yarn (heel) Patons Kroy Socks, Colour Coal   Pattern (leg/foot) Pennants Socks   Pattern (heel) Mina&amp;rsquo;s Vanilla Sock Recipe, with high-instep option   Size 64 stitch   Ribbing 2×2 ribbing for 16 rounds (1 1&amp;frasl;2&amp;rdquo;)   Leg Length 5×12 row repeats (60 rounds) (not including ribbing)   Foot Length 6×12 row repeats (72 rounds) (not including toe)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vanilla is the New Black</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/post/vanilla_new_black/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2018 21:08:22 -0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/post/vanilla_new_black/</guid>
      <description>This is pair number four complete, and less than two months in. I&amp;rsquo;m getting far enough ahead of pace that I might be able to take on some other projects and not let this one down. This was a new heel pattern for me, and I&amp;rsquo;m still not sure if I like it or not; I&amp;rsquo;ll have to see how it fits, but I usually like a contrast heel (partially for looks, partially so that I don&amp;rsquo;t run out of yarn) which this doesn&amp;rsquo;t really allow for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alpaca Gingham Socks</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/post/alpaca_gingham_socks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2018 13:41:02 -0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/post/alpaca_gingham_socks/</guid>
      <description>Socks five and six (pair three) have been completed. These are sport weight ones, so they went pretty fast, even with the pattern. I used two complete balls (less than 1g left over of each) of the main colour, and about 75% of a ball of the black.
Finished socks.
Pattern close up.
   Sock Details      Yarn (main) Sandnes Garn Alpakka Strømpegarn, Colour 1053   Yarn (heel, toe, cuff) Sandnes Garn Alpakka Strømpegarn, Colour 1099   Pattern (leg/foot) Gingham Socks   Pattern (heel) Mina&amp;rsquo;s Vanilla Sock Recipe, with high-instep option   Size 56 stitch   Ribbing 2×2 ribbing for 14 rounds (1 1&amp;frasl;2&amp;rdquo;)   Leg Length 8×8 row repeats (64 rounds (6 1&amp;frasl;2&amp;rdquo;) (not including ribbing)   Foot Length 7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green/Yellow Socks</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/post/green_yellow_socks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 14:02:02 -0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/post/green_yellow_socks/</guid>
      <description>The second pair have been completed. This uses up the last of the Drops Fabel that I have on hand. These knit up pretty quickly, especially after coming off a patterned pair.
Finished socks.
   Sock Details      Yarn (main) Drops Fabel Print, Colour 452   Yarn (heel) Patons Kroy Socks, Colour Coal   Pattern Mina&amp;rsquo;s Vanilla Sock Recipe, with high-instep option   Size 64 stitch   Ribbing 2×2 ribbing for 16 rounds (1 1&amp;frasl;2&amp;rdquo;)   Leg Length 72 rounds (6 1&amp;frasl;4&amp;rdquo;) (not including ribbing)   Foot Length 72 rounds (6 1&amp;frasl;4&amp;rdquo;) (not including toe)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beard Hat</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/post/beard_hat/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2018 17:04:59 -0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/post/beard_hat/</guid>
      <description>I took a quick break from socks (as I&amp;rsquo;m currently ahead of schedule with three of twenty-four socks complete) to crochet my son a bearded hat for his birthday. It was a really quick project; if I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to rip it out several times to get the fit right, it would have been finished in two evenings. It was my first time doing the &amp;lsquo;bobble stitch&amp;rsquo; for the beard&amp;ndash;they&amp;rsquo;re also not difficult, but they do slow things down a bit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basket Rib Socks</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/post/basket_rib_socks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2018 13:41:02 -0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/post/basket_rib_socks/</guid>
      <description>The first pair of socks have been completed. I cast on the first one on New Year&amp;rsquo;s Day, and started the second one on January 5. The texture sort of got lost in the print nature of the yarn, so I may revisit this pattern again later on a plain yarn. I would have gone for a single-colour yarn this time, but the only ones I have on hand are lighter, and I have to go down a needle size and up to a 72 stitch sock to not get laddering.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pace Socks</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/post/pace_socks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2017 10:51:53 -0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/post/pace_socks/</guid>
      <description>I cast on these socks on the night of December 1. I wanted to see just how long it would take me to knit a pair of vanilla socks, to see how realistic this project actually is (for me, I know for some people twenty-four socks in twelve months is no stretch at all). This was certainly the fastest that I&amp;rsquo;ve knit a pair, it was less than two weeks in total, and I had a couple of evenings with no knitting at all in there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Status</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/page/status/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 10:50:59 -0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/page/status/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 09:17:07 -0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/page/about/</guid>
      <description>By day, I&amp;rsquo;m an entrepreneur, software developer, and electronics designer. By night, I&amp;rsquo;m a woodworker, knitter, and crocheter.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been knitting since October 2016 (and crocheting since June 2016), and have knit six pairs of socks before starting this project.
The goal of this site it to document my progress (and keep me honest) on knitting twenty-four socks (ideally twelve pairs) in 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Rules</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/page/rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 08:55:36 -0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/page/rules/</guid>
      <description>These are the rules that I&amp;rsquo;ve laid out for myself for the project so far. These are subject to change, but I suspect I&amp;rsquo;ll only make them more restrictive, not less.
 All socks need to be sized for an adult foot (baby and child socks do not count). All socks must be started and completed in the project timeframe. For a sock to be &amp;ldquo;completed&amp;rdquo; it needs to be bound off with all ends woven in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Project</title>
      <link>http://24sockproject.me/post/this_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Dec 2017 21:20:51 -0330</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://24sockproject.me/post/this_project/</guid>
      <description>The purpose of this site is to document the progress of my 2018 goal to knit twelve pairs of socks (thus the 24 socks). I&amp;rsquo;ve been knitting since October 2016 (and crocheting since June 2016), and have knit six pairs of socks.
In preparation for the project, I have picked up Socktacular and Artful Arches from Knit Picks and enough yarn for five pairs of socks.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>